<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>To the High Court of Parliament: the humble remonstrance of the Company of Stationers, London.</title>
            <author>Stationers' Company (London, England)</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1643</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 21 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">A91370</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing P425</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Thomason E247_23</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R206828</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">99865933</idno>
            <idno type="PROQUEST">99865933</idno>
            <idno type="VID">158416</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. A91370)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 158416)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Thomason Tracts ; 42:E247[23])</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>To the High Court of Parliament: the humble remonstrance of the Company of Stationers, London.</title>
                  <author>Stationers' Company (London, England)</author>
                  <author>Parker, Henry, 1604-1652.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[8] p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>s.n.,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>[London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1643]</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Imprint from Wing.</note>
                  <note>Annotation on Thomason copy: "Aprill 1643"; "By Henry Parker Esq:".</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of the original in the British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Stationers' Company (London, England) --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Printing --  Great Britain --  Early works to 1800.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-08</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-10</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-10</date>
            <label>Simon Charles</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="remonstrance">
            <pb facs="tcp:158416:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>To the High Court of PARLIAMENT: The humble REMONSTRANCE of the Company of <hi>Stationers,</hi> LONDON.</head>
            <opener>Sheweth,</opener>
            <p>THat the Myſtery and Art of Printing is of pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like and great Importance, and ought to be held worthy of extraordinary regard and conſidera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion, in all well-govern'd States. <hi>China</hi> ha<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ving had the uſe of Printing and Guns, long be<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore they were invented in <hi>Europe,</hi> makes no doubt to magnifie her ſelf, as ſeeing with two Eyes; whereas <hi>Europe</hi> (as ſhe pretends) ſees but with one. And in <hi>Europe</hi> the more civill and knowing each Countrey is, the more care<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fully they provide for the proſperity of this ingenious Craft, and it were ſtrange if they ſhould not; for as Learning muſt needs make us favour Printing, ſo Printing is a great means to advance Learning amongſt us. But <hi>France</hi> eſpecially is famous for the value ſhe ſets upon that Profeſſion and Trade of men (whom we in <hi>England</hi> incorporate by the name of Stationers) for there they are priviledged above meer Mechanicks, and ho<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>noured with a habitation, as it were, in the Suburbs of Litera<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture it ſelf. The like reaſon alſo which makes Printing, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> favoured and promoted in generous Countries where Learning is eſteemed, renders it odious amongſt Barbarians, where ſu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>perſtition and darkneſſe is affected. <hi>Muſcovy</hi> profeſſes enmity to Printing, and ſo does <hi>Turkie,</hi> for Learning's ſake: And there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore the ſetting up of a Greek Preſſe at <hi>Conſtantinople,</hi> ſent thi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ther out of <hi>England,</hi> had like to have coſt <hi>Cyrillus</hi> the Patriarke there his Life, and the Greeks their fatall Ruine, <hi>Turk. hiſt. pag.</hi> 1491. Nevertheleſſe, it is not meere Printing, but well ordered Printing that merits ſo much favour and reſpect, ſince in things precious and excellent, the abuſe (if not prevented) is commonly as dangerous, as the uſe is advantagious. <hi>Germany</hi> had the happy Sagacity to invent Preſſes, Watches, &amp;c. yet now, for want of reglement, her reputation is loſt in thoſe Manufactures, a Ger<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>man Impreſſion, or Watch, <hi>eo nomine,</hi> is undervalued. In the
<pb facs="tcp:158416:2"/> United-Provinces alſo, there are not above three or foure Emi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nent and rich Printers by reaſon of ill order, and were it not for the great Stocks of Moneyes which enable thoſe men to print the greater Volumes, and of more generall uſe, that Trade would there alſo further yet decay. And commonly where Printing droops, and Printers grow poor by neglect of Go<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vernment, there errors and hereſies abound, alſo by the ſame neglect as in <hi>Poland,</hi> and ſome parts of the Netherlands is ma<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nifeſt, where the poyſon of <hi>Socinus</hi> and <hi>Arminius</hi> ſpreads un<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>regarded. We muſt in this give Papiſts their due; for as well where the Inquiſition predominates, as not, regulation is more ſtrict by far, then it is amongſt Proteſtants; we are not ſo wiſe in our Generation, nor take ſo much care to preſerve the true Religion as they do the falſe from alteration: and for that cauſe not onely their Church is the more fortified, but the Art of Printing thrives, and the Artiſts grow rich alſo beyond any examples amongſt us. The firſt and greateſt end of order in the Preſſe, is the advancement of wholeſome knowledge, and this end is meerly publike: But that ſecond end which pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>vides for the proſperity of Printing and Printers, is not meer<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ly private, partly becauſe the benefit of ſo conſiderable a Body is of concernment to the whole; and partly becauſe the com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſſing of the ſecond end does much conduce to the accom<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pliſhing of the firſt, as is now to be further explained: For, upon further examination, it muſt needs cleerly appear, That the late decay of the Stationers (chiefly brought upon them by want of due and Politick regulation) has been an occaſion of emboldning Printers to run into enormious diſorders, and in the like manner the ſame diſorders have been a further occaſion of bringing a decay upon the Company. <hi>England</hi> was not heretofore without a regulation in Printing, as well knowing that the publike good was very much concerned in that Art, and that no act did more depend upon the publike Care. Whole<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſome Ordinances therefore were provided and great circum<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpection was uſed, that thoſe Ordinances might be punctually purſued. In the 8<hi rend="sup">th</hi> and 28<hi rend="sup">th</hi> of Qu: <hi>Eliz.</hi> divers good De<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>crees were made; and in the fourth of Qu: <hi>Eliz.</hi> ſuch Orders of the ſame nature as had been before in force, were reviſed and approved of by our Reverend Judges <hi>Catlyn</hi> and <hi>Dyer.</hi> Alſo the third and fourth of <hi>Edw.</hi> ſixth; and the third of King <hi>James;</hi> and other Statutes need not now to be inſtanced in.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:158416:2"/>
            <p n="1">1. But as to the firſt and publike aym of regulation in Print<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, <hi>&amp;c. Viz.</hi> The advancement of Knowledge, <hi>&amp;c.</hi> The main care is to appoint ſevere Examiners for the licenſing of things profitable, and ſuppreſſing of things harmfull: and the next Care is, That the endeavours of thoſe Examiners may not be fruſtrated. The Starre-Chamber, and High Commiſſion Court is now removed, and for ſupply of that Government which is faln therewithall, a new Bill is to be paſſed in Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament; and till that Bill can be paſſed, ſundry good temporary Orders have been made to redreſſe the exorbitancies of the Preſſe. Nevertheleſſe, tis too apparent, that thoſe Orders have not been ſo ſucceſſefull as was wiſhed and expected; and ſince the want of ſucceſſe therein, cannot be imputed to the change of Judges, or change of Laws, it muſt needs be imputed to the change of proſecutors. The Parliament wants no power to puniſh Delinquents, the Orders of the Parliament want no vigour for ſearching of Printers houſes, and ſeiz<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing, taking away and defacing the Inſtruments of Printing, and for puniſhing and impriſoning all Delinquents; onely thoſe that are the moſt fit Informers, want authority and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couragement to diſcover offences to the Parliament, or to put in execution the Orders of Parliament. The Stationers there<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fore humbly deſire to repreſent three things to the Parliament: 1. That the Life of all Law conſiſts in proſecution. 2. That in matters of the Preſſe, no man can ſo effectually proſecute, as Stationers themſelves. 3. That if Stationers at this preſent do not ſo zealouſly proſecute as is deſired, it is to be underſtood, That it is partly for want of full authority, and partly for want of true encouragement.</p>
            <p n="2">2. In the next place alſo, as to the ſecond aym of regulation, <hi>viz.</hi> The flouriſhing of Printing and Printers; the Stationers further humbly deſire, That their advantage and benefit may be ſo far onely tendred and regarded, as it co-operates to the due ordering and reforming of the Preſſe; That authority and en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>couragement which they ſeek for, to engage them to activity and alacrity in this ſervice of the State, if it be not ſuch as is conſiſtent with the publike good, if it be not agreeable to the Diſcipline of former times, if it be not vigorous and efficaci<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous for the Reformation of Printing deſired, they ſhall be no longer Suitors for it. As for matter of power, 'tis not the de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire of the Stationers to be ſolely or confuſedly entruſted with
<pb facs="tcp:158416:3"/> the Government of the Preſſe: They deſire no authority in or<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>der to judgement or puniſhment, but onely in order to proſecu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tion of Delinquents; and that power alſo they deſire not to have it committed to the whole Company (though that lately hath expreſſed a good affection to the Parliament) but to ſome choice Committee, nominated by the Company, and further approved and allowed by the Parliament. Neither is it the Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioners deſire that this Committee of the choiceſt Stationers ſhould be enabled with too vaſt a Latitude of making Orders to binde the whole Company in all caſes whatſoever, ſuch li<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mits as other Companies are confined to, ſuch as preceding Sta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tioners have ſubmitted to, ſuch as are conſiſtent with the pub<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>like good, and Laws of the Land (according to their Charters granted by ſeverall Princes) ſuch and no other do they aſpire to. But ſome abuſes there are likely to ariſe emergently, which without extraordinary proviſions <hi>pro re natâ,</hi> can ſcarcely be ſuppreſſed; and therefore that favour which they deſire, is, That they may not be abridged of all power in this kind. Within theſe laſt four yeers, the affairs of the Preſſe have grown very ſcandal<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ous and enormious, and all redreſſe is almoſt impoſſible, if power be not given by ſome binding order to reduce Preſſes and Apprentices to the proportion of thoſe times which did pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cede theſe laſt four yeers. This is ſo farre from an Innovation, that tis the removall of a dangerous Innovation, and without this removall, the Company of Stationers being like a field overpeſtred with too much ſtock, muſt needs grow indigent, and indigence muſt needs make it run into treſpaſſes, and break out into divers unlawfull ſhifts; as Cattle uſe to do, when their paſture begins wholly to fail. Beſides the ſame diſorder which undoes Stationers by too great multitudes of Preſſes and Ap<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>prentices amongſt themſelves, cauſes alſo Strangers, as Dra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>pers, Carmen, and others to break in upon them, and ſet up Preſſes in divers obſcure corners of the City, and Suburbs; ſo that not onely the ruine of the Company is the more haſtened by it, but alſo the miſchief, which the ſtate ſuffers by the irre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>gularity of all is the leſſe remediable. <hi>A multis quicquid pecca<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tur, inultum eſt.</hi> Where Delinquents grow too numerous, they grow out of the Eye of government; tis not poſſible for the Stationers themſelves at this day to diſcover their own treſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>paſſors, and tis not poſſible that the State ſhould any way have the ſteering of the Preſſe, when Stationers cannot aſſiſt them therein.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:158416:3"/>
            <p>This is of main conſequence; For were there but a modeſt limited power in the Stationers to reduce Preſſes and Appren<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tices to a convenient number, by advice amongſt themſelves, the reformation of the Preſſe, would become a feaſible thing; not onely all odious opprobrious Pamphlets of incendiaries, Printed and invented at <hi>London,</hi> but penned in the Univerſities alſo, and re-Printed at <hi>London</hi> would be quaſhed: by the ſame means alſo, the ſhamefull cuſtome of ſelling Pamphlets by Sempſters, &amp;c. and diſperſing them in the ſtreets by Emiſſaries of ſuch baſe condition; and the abuſe of Printing in ſuch de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſpicable Letters, and baſe Paper, and many other exorbitances, now offenſive to the whole age, would be rectified.</p>
            <p n="3">3. The next thing is matter of priviledge or encouragement; As the caſe now ſtands, Stationers are ſo farre from having any encouragement to make them active and alacrious in the ſervice of the ſtate, that they cannot ſerve it without diſcouragement; and they are ſo farre from enjoying priviledge, that they are abridged of their ancient Right, Propriety of Copies being now almoſt taken away and confounded, if one Stationer pre<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ferre any Complaint againſt another, the Complainant ſhall be ſure to have his Copy re-Printed out of ſpite, and ſo the ruine of himſelf and family, is made the reward of his zeal and for<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wardneſſe. And to inſtance onely in propriety of Copies, that in ſome mens underſtanding, is the ſame thing as a Monoply: Though it be not ſo much a free priviledge as a neceſſary right to Stationers; without which they cannot at all ſubſiſt, Yet ſome men except againſt it as a publike injury and grievance. Nevertheleſſe, Juſtice and Policy depend as much upon pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>priety of ſome things, as upon Community of others; and 'twould as much diſſolve the bonds of humane ſociety, to lay open ſome benefits of nature, as to incloſe others. Therefore that an orderly preſervation of private Intereſt, and propriety in Copies is a thing many wayes beneficiall to the ſtate, and different in nature from the engroſſing, or Monopolizing ſome other Commodities into the hands of a few, to the producing ſcarcity and dearth, amongſt the generality. The Stationers de<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſire leave to offer theſe conſiderations.</p>
            <p n="1">1. Books (except the ſacred Bible) are not of ſuch generall uſe and neceſſity, as ſome ſtaple Commodities are, which feed and cloath us, nor are they ſo periſhable, or require charge in keeping, ſome of them being once bought, remain to Childrens
<pb facs="tcp:158416:4"/> Children, and many of them are rarities onely and uſefull only to a very few, and of no neceſſity to any, few men beſtow more in Books then what they can ſpare out of their ſuperflui<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, and the gain of ſuch as live by ſelling of Books is not ſo great, as to raiſe them to an equality of riches with many o<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>thers of more ſordid and ignoble profeſſions. And therefore propriety in Books maintained amongſt Stationers, cannot have the ſame effect, in order to the publike, as it has in other Commodities of more publike uſe and neceſſity.</p>
            <p n="2">2. A well regulated propriety of Copies amongſt Stationers, makes Printing flouriſh, and Books more plentifull and cheap; whereas Community (though it ſeeme not ſo, at firſt, to ſuch as look leſſe ſeriouſly, and intentively upon it) brings in con<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fuſion, and many other diſorders both to the damage of the State and the Company of Stationers alſo; and this will many wayes be evidenced. For firſt, If it be lawfull for all men to Print all Copies, At the ſame time ſeverall men will either enviouſly, or ignorantly Print the ſame thing, and ſo perhaps undo one another, and bring in a great waſte of the Commo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dities, whereby the State ſhall be at loſſe, and diſcord, and enmities will alſo follow, whereby Chriſtianity it ſelf ſhall be ſcandalized. Secondly, The fear of this confuſion will hinder many men from Printing at all, to the great obſtruction of Learning, and ſuppreſſion of many excellent and worthy peeces. Doctor <hi>Preſton,</hi> Doctor <hi>Sibbs</hi> his works, a large Concordance for the Bible, and very many other Books of ſingular uſe and eſteem, are now out of Print, and the age muſt ſtill be deprived of them, for no man dares, or can with ſafety Print them. In other Countries where regulation is ſtrict, the Tomes and Volumes of Fathers and Schoolmen, and ſome Books with coſtly Plates, are Printed to the honour and bene<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>fit of the publike many wayes, whereas the Printing of Pam<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>phlets is now the utmoſt ambition of Stationers in <hi>England.</hi> And even in Pamphlets too there is a great hazard, for ſcarce one book of three ſells well, or proves gainfull to the publiſher, and therefore the certaine charge of Printing being ſo great, and the profit ſo unſure, it is no policy to venture too far. Thirdly, Confuſion or Community of Copies deſtroyes that Commerce amongſt Stationers, whereby by way of Barter and Exchange they furniſh bookes without money one to another, and are en<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>abled thereby to print with leſſe hazard, and to ſell to other men
<pb facs="tcp:158416:4"/> for leſſe profit. Fourthly, Community as it diſcourages Stati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners, ſo it's a great diſcouragement to the Authors of Books alſo; Many mens ſtudies carry no other profit or recompence with them, but the benefit of their Copies; and if this be ta<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ken away, many Pieces of great worth and excellence will be ſtrangled in the womb, or never conceived at all for the fu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ture. Fifthly, In many caſes Community will injuſtice, as well as diſcouragement; for many Families have now their Lively-hoods by Aſſignments of Copies, ſome Orphans and Widows have no other Legacies and Dowries to depend upon: and there is no reaſon apparent why the production of the Brain ſhould not be as aſſignable, and their intereſt and poſſeſ<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſion (being of more rare, ſublime, and publike uſe, demerit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing the higheſt encouragement) held as tender in Law, as the right of any Goods or Chattells whatſoever. And as theſe and many other are the miſchiefs of Community, redounding ſo many ſeverall wayes to Authors, Owners, to Printers, to the State, and to the Church, ſo propriety produces the contra<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ry effects; for he that is ſure of his Copy, though the ſame coſt 3 or 400<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>. if he cannot raiſe his money disburſed at the firſt Impreſſion, yet being aſſured of benefit by after Editions, he may ſell cheaper at firſt then he buyes, to the great eaſe of other men. Beſides, it will be a means to relieve the po<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verty of the Company of Stationers, and by that means reme<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dy thoſe many diſorders which neceſſarily attend poverty; and if any diſorders happen, it will animate and ſharpen Stati<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>oners to be zealous in detecting them, and bringing the offend<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ers to condign puniſhment: And as this may be truely ſaid in defence of Propriety, as it concerns private men in their In<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tereſts, ſo much more may be ſaid for Propriety of ſuch Copies as the whole Company have a Right in, the good of ſo many hundreds being far more conſiderable then the good of any par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ticular (which cannot be reputed a Monopoly, though of com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon and univerſall uſe, becauſe common to the entire Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>feſſion.) For ſince Propriety has been confounded, and their Intereſt loſt in thoſe Copies which anciently belonged to them, the whole Company (whoſe chief, and almoſt ſole Revenues and ſupport, was the annuall benefit accrewing from their Copies now Printed from them) has drooped and grown poor. It has no common ſtock to provide Magazines of Corn, Arms, &amp;c. for the States neceſſities, nor to pay Subſidies,
<pb facs="tcp:158416:5"/> or other frequent Aſſeſſements, charged by Parliament; nor to maintain their poor, being many, and requiring 200<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap> 
               <hi>per annum.</hi> And all the freehold they now have belonging to the Corporation, together with their Common-ſeal, lyes at this preſent engaged for 1500<gap reason="illegible" resp="#OXF" extent="1 letter">
                  <desc>•</desc>
               </gap>, borrowed lately at intereſt for the ſervice of the Parliament. Nor have they ſo much as a Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mon-Hall of their own to aſſemble in; nor can they any lon<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ger remain incorporate, or any way priviledged by their Char<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ter, but muſt immediately moulder away, and diſſolve without ſome redreſſe of this irregularity.</p>
            <p>More of propriety needs not be ſaid, nor of any other do<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>meſticall Priviledges or Rights belonging to the Stationers. And for forraign abuſes, little need to be alleadged. Tis obvious to all, That (if we will eſtabliſh a juſt regulation) forraign Books muſt be ſubjected to examination, as well as our own, and that all ſuch Importation of forraign Books ought to be reſtrained as tends to the diſadvantage of our native Stationers. By the firſt of <hi>Richard</hi> the third, forraign Books were allowed, the manufacture of Printing being then rude, and imperfect in <hi>England.</hi> But by the 25 of <hi>Henry</hi> 8. the Engliſh being then grown more expert, for their benefit it was repealed. And in <hi>France</hi> where Printing eminently flouriſhes, if any Books be brought from <hi>Geneva</hi> to <hi>Lyons,</hi> or from <hi>Lyons</hi> to <hi>Paris</hi> Printed there, they are ſeized by the Searchers, and confiſcate without remedy; And nothing conduceth more to the flouriſhing of that profeſſion there, then this rigid and ſevere obſervance of regulation.</p>
            <p>
               <hi>Now therefore all theſe premiſes conſidered, and foraſmuch as irregular Printing, hath of late been the fewell in ſome mea<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſure of this miſerable Civill-Warre, by deceiving the multi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tude, and hath brought into both Church and State, ſundry other miſchiefs and miſeries, as well as poverty and deſolation upon the Corporation of Stationers. It is moſt humbly prayed, That ſome ſpeedy courſe may be taken for ſuch a perfect regu<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>lation of the Preſſe, as may procure the publike good of the State, by the private prosperity of the Stationers Company.</hi>
            </p>
            <p>
               <hi>And the whole Company ſhall ever pray, &amp;c.</hi>
            </p>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>
